<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taylor Twardowski</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Taylor Twardowski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Python!</title>
      <link>/post/2021/05/05/learning-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/05/05/learning-python/</guid>
      <description>We’ve been learning Python recently in our Computational Biology class, so I thought I would share some of the basics and include how R and Python are able to “talk” to each other, through the use of reticulation.
#Python For Python basics, I wanted to showcase how lists can be utilized, and replacements within those can be made through modifications.
Below I generate a list, called “list1” with the numbers 1, 2, 3 and 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Plans</title>
      <link>/post/2021/05/05/summer-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/05/05/summer-plans/</guid>
      <description>I am very excited to use this summer to relax and recharge. I was hoping to get an internship, however, I began applying for opportunities later than I had originally hoped. I’m now planning to use my free time to work, relax, and take a mental break before starting up in the fall. I’m not one to love taking breaks, but I think this one is quite necessary. More updates to come!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The two datasets being analyzed are ExerciseHours and Pulse. They were acquired through R Studio packages (Lock5Data and Stat2Data) present within the software. I have always been very into exercising and wanted to assess how exercise and pulse rates (both active and resting) relate to each other, if at all. Though the Pulse dataset includes much of this information, the goal is to incorporate the ExerciseHours dataset to better understand the relationships present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The data set being analyzed here is called Participation; it contains 872 observations with a total of 8 variables, to measure the work force participation in Switzerland. The “X1” variable gives a number to each individual whose data was collected. The “lfp” variable shows labor force participation status with either “yes” or “no”. The “lnnlinc” variable gives the log of the non-labor income. The “age” variable gives the age of the individual in years divided by 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis
 Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
